

# **DHIMAN TALAPATRA** Full Stack Developer





Full Stack Engineer with Cloud Development experience. 10+ years of industry experience in delivering solutions for Banking and Telecom Domain across multiple technologies including CI/CD, UX, Cloud etc Technologies. AWS Developer Associate, CSM Scrum Master certified, having experience in managing and collaborating with various teams to deliver on time solutions.



+91 9874380099

✓ dhiman.talapatra@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhiman-talapatra

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Jul 2018 - Present Cognizant Technology solutions

Senior Associate

Offshore Lead / Scrum Master of 11-member team, Occasional Academy Trainer, Full Stack Developer, Cloud developer, UX developer, Automation Lead

#### Dec 2014 - Jun 2018 Cognizant Technology solutions

**Associate** 

Offshore Lead of 5-member team, Occasional Academy Trainer, Full Stack developer, UX developer

#### Jul 2014 - Oct 2014 HCL Technologies Limited

**Lead Engineer** 

Team lead of 3-member team, Full stack Java Developer

#### Oct 2012 - Jun 2014 HCL Technologies Limited

**Software Engineer** 

Full Stack Java Developer, Selenium automation developer

#### Feb 2011 - Oct 2012 Infosys Limited

Senior Systems Engineer

Java developer in Finacle Banking solution

## Feb 2010 - Jan 2011 Infosys Limited

**Systems Engineer** 

Junior Java developer in Finacle Banking solution

#### **SKILLS**

#### Cloud

AWS, OpenShift3, Heroku, Flrebase

## **DevOps**

Jenkins, Git-Lab CI/CD, Heroku Pipeline

## Containerization

Docker, Kubernetes

#### Java

Core Java, Spring, JSF

#### **Front-End**

Angular, React, Bootstrap CSS

#### **Mobile**

Android, PWA

#### **Other Languages**

Kotlin, Python, Unix Shell Script

## **Big Data**

Hadoop

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

# **Nov 2020** AWS Certified Developer - Associate (DVA)

Amazon Simple Queue Service, Amazon DynamoDB, Amazon ElastiCache, Amazon Kinesis, AWS Lambda, Amazon API Gateway, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, AWS Identity and Access Management, AWS Key Management Service.

## Jun 2019 CSM Certified Scrum Master

Agile Methodology, Roles and responsibilities of scrum master ,Various SCRUM parameters and measures, SCRUM ceremonies.

## Mar 2019 Knowledge Stalwarts

Recognition of excellence in training and consistent high feedback from training participants.

## Oct 2018 Full Stack Engineer

Angular (Angular material), Docker, Spring Boot (Secure REST PI with token based authentication), MySQL

## Jul 2014 Hadoop and BIG data

concepts of Hadoop Distributed File System and MapReduce, Setup a Hadoop Cluster, Understand Data Loading Techniques using Sqoop and Flume, Perform Data Analytics using Pig and Hive, Work on a Real Life Project on Big Data Analytics and gain Hands on Project Experience

# **EDUCATION**

2005 - 2009

Graduation - B.TECH - Electronics & Instrumentation Guru Nanak Institute of Technology, Sodepur

2003 - 2005

Senior Secondary - Science ST Xavier's Institution, Panihati

2002 - 2002 Secondary

Douglas Memorial High School, Barrackpore

# **PERSONAL INFO**

Date of Birth **Nationality** Gender **Marital Status** Indian 30th April 1987 Male Married

## Address

43/B Rabindrapalli Netaji Road, Barrackpore, Kolkata-700122.

# **Languages Known**

Bengali, English, Hindi

## **Blood Group**

# **Passport Number**

H6701325